# Ranvijay Sachan

#### Career Highlights:

Total Exp: 8+ years

Experience in developing applications from scratch and have the experience of building a product end to end. Maintaining and Optimizing back end code for scalability and better Performance Test Driven Development Architecture.Building restful api's using python, django/rest framework.

#### PERSONAL INFO

**Father**: Birendra K. Sachan **Mother**: Arunima Sachan **Languages**: Hindi, English

**DOB**: 05-06-1986 **PAN**: FVYPS2996K

## **EXPERIENCE (8+ years)**

**Aricent technologies**, Gurgaon - *Technical Lead* (Oct 2017- Current)

**Zymr System**, Pune - *Sr. Software Engineer (***August 2016 - Sep-2017**)

Incredible Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai - *SDE-*1 (July 2015 - Jul 2016)

**SRM Techsol. Pvt. Ltd**, Lucknow - *Software Engineer* 

(Aug 2011 - June 2015)

#### **HONOR & AWARDS**

- Employee of month Award in 2014
- CEO Appreciation award in 2016
- Team Excellence Award in 2017

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Application(MCA)
From Integral University, Lucknow - with 84%.

Address: Gurgaon, Haryana, India Email: sachan.ranvijay@gmail.com Mo: +91- 9987391275, 9319741275 Linkedin GitHub StackOverflow Website

#### **SKILLS**

**Languages**: **Python**, JavaScript, Html, Sql, shellScript, Java(Basic)

OS: Ubuntu, windows, Mac

Web Server: Apache2, Nginx, wisgi, asgi

Frameworks: Django, Django-Rest, Scrapy, ScrapyD, flask, ORM, whoosh, solar, pandas, RabbitMq, celery, redis, JWT, oauth2, AzureAd, Docker, React kubernetes, microservices etc..

**Integration**: **AWS**(bucket, SES, bolo, s3), Gupshup, Zoho, **salesforce**, twitter Api's, Logging(loggly), elasticsearch-dsl

**DB**: Mysql, **postgres**, sqlLite, Elastic, Whoosh, Hdf5, **mongoDB** etc.

**Tools/OS**: Pycharm,**GIT**, **Jenkins**(CI/CD), JIRA, Postman, Jmeter, **Swagger** etc...

#### **Security Tools:**

Nmap, **Nessus**, **Qark**, Sonarqube, **Openscap**, Dagda, Blackduck, Burpsuite etc..

### **Projects:**

- Avert (Automated Vulnerability Ecosystem Resistance tactics)
- Design Hub
- Credr
- Cartwire
- Salesify
- Adobe TV
- CardioVIP

## Languages

- English
- Hindi